Zach Cohen

User Experience Researcher & Designer I zach-cohen.com

My background and work experience are focused on how we interact with the world around us. Through design and research, I am mindful of the entire lifecycle of a product and its business impact. My goal is to help improve systems for groups working in the life sciences and leverage artificial intelligence for public health and biology solutions.

Experience

Bentley University User Experience Center

Research and Design Associate | 2021 - 2022

- Consulted with clients such as Boston Scientific, Ginkgo Bioworks, and Philips Healthcare.
- Developed and moderated usability tests and interviews for medical device FDA approval.
- Qualitative and quantitative data analysis, insight synthesis, presentation of findings and recommendations.
- Conducted accessibility audits of physical and digital products to improve WCAG compliance.

Integrate Inc.

Product Designer I 2019 - 2021

- Established a design system guild to guide best practices and overall progression.
- Partnered with product management to conduct discovery and define software features.
- Led design and product-informed strategy for several product development teams.
- Prototyped, user tested, and collaborated with engineering to implement and ship designs.
- Developed user research initiatives to improve integration of research into the product development process.

InEight

Interaction Designer (Contract) | 2018 - 2019

- Translated design vision established through research to update legacy product.
- Worked closely with product and development teams to add and refine product features.
- Led user experience optimization alongside key stakeholders and product management.

Nucleus Marketing Lab

User Researcher (Contract) | 2018 - 2018

 Helped recognize user behavior and re-frame product development goals through qualitative and quantitative research and analysis.

Education

Bentley University

M.S. – Human Factors in Information Design Expected Graduation 2022

Designlab

Certificate - User Experience Design Graduated 2018

Woodbury University

B.A. – Interdisciplinary Studies (Psychology and Interior Architecture Emphases)

Graduated 2017

Skills

Research: Data analysis • Persona & User journey
 Generative research • Usability testing • Card
 sorting • Tree testing • Contextual Inquiry •
 Ethnography • Surveys • Interviewing • Diary
 Study • Workshop facilitation

Design: Interaction design • Wireframing • Prototyping • Interface design • Product strategy

Software and applications

Figma HTML Adobe XD CSS

Dovetail Survey Monkey

Qualtrics Statistical Analysis

Volunteer Experience

Machine Learning in UX Meetup: Event writing, outreach, community building

Emergency Design Collective: Research for K-3 students learning at home during the pandemic

Topics of Interest

Healthcare/Personal Health AI/ML

Accessibility Bio/Data Ethics